AMALDI TRI SEPTYANTO

amalditris@gmail.com | +6287879511259 | linkedin.com/in/amaldits

SUMMARY

Electrical Engineering graduate with one year of hands-on experience with embedded systems. Inquisitive and eager to work on a large-scale Internet of Things integrated with other disciplines, so that all the information in it can be a source for better management decision-making in the future. I am also interested in robotics and would like to learn more about how to use the control or mathematical knowledge to help us make a better technology for society.

EXPERIENCE

PT. ARIA AGRI INDONESIA – Jakarta, Indonesia

Firmware Engineer

Mar 2022 - Sep 2023

- Designed and created firmware for a device called Worker Tracker for data acquisition of field worker footprint so the data can be transmitted by file transfer protocol communication to a single board computer before transmitting the data to the cloud
- Designed and created firmware for a device called Turbo Spreader for the application of fertilizer spreader to calculate how much fertilizer is on the field for each coordinate, and served the data to a data platform application, so this device can help monitor fertilizer use day by day
- Maintained the firmware to implement clean code so that it is well-documented and organized
- Reported work and progress by doing daily standups before work and sprint review at the end of the week

PT. Movus Technologies Indonesia – Bandung, Indonesia

Firmware Engineer Intern

Aug 2021 - Oct 2021

- Increasing performance by created and refactored 60% of subfeatures for hardware to help the purpose of the application to track the activity of the user who buys a car through movus
- Found and debugged the 30% bugs that occur when making the firmware itself
- Reporting progress making firmware related in weekly scrum every day on daily scrum meetings

PT. IROSTech Solusi Inteligen – Bandung, Indonesia

Engineer Intern

May 2019 – Aug 2019

- Created a prototype to develop IoT (Internet of Things) technologies for household purposes using ESP32 as a microcontroller to control sensor and actuator
- Created a simple dashboard apps with a web-based as interface for users to control sensor and actuator through microcontroller up to 80% of finished

PROJECTS

Institut Teknologi Bandung - Bandung, Indonesia

Part-Time Research Assistant on Autonomous Tram Project

Oct 2021 – Apr 2022

- This project is a collaboration between ITB (*Institut Teknologi Bandung*), INKA (*Industri Kereta Api*), riset.ai, and LPDP (*Lembaga Pengelola Dana Pendidikan*) which aims to create a tram that can run autonomously
- Created a program to logging environment data such as tram waypoint coordinate from GNSS (Global Navigation Satellite System), pointcloud data from LIDAR (Light Detection and Ranging)
- Designed a first prototype of power system for powering all sensor and the computer for logical calculation which will be used in the Autonomous Tram
- Reporting the progress twice a week related scrum assignment last week before

Part-Time Research Assistant on Autonomous Forklift Project

Oct 2021 – Mar 2022

- This project is a collaboration between ITB (*Institut Teknologi Bandung*), and CPIN (*Charoen Pokphand Indonesia Tbk*) which aims to create a forklift that can run autonomously, and locating itself in indoor facility
- Conducted research about mobile robot localization using Adaptive Monte Carlo Localization for Prototype of Autonomous Forklift using ROS (Robot Operating System) as framework and Gazebo as simulator

Research Assistant on Laboratory of Advance Robotic ITB

Sep 2020 - Aug 2021

- Created a platform for developing an autonomous drone that can autonomously inspect the damage, such as crack, moss, lumpy surface, on the bridge structures
- Reporting the research on thesis "Visual Investigation of Bridge Damage Using Autonomous Drone" from proposal until testing phase every month

ORGANIZATIONAL EXPERIENCE

EMBARGO 2018 - Bandung, Indonesia

Leader

Aug 2017 - April 2018

- EMBARGO stands for Empati Berbagi Bersama Allegro. Its a social activites carried out by electrical engineering students during their second year
- Made 20 teaching tools to help elementary school students study and enthusiasticly about understanding the lessons taught by their teachers
- Manage 100 less electrical engineering students to complete this event in 6 months of preparation
- Report all matters from proposal until the event itself in accountablity trial at the electrical student association

KRSBI-H ITB Team - Bandung, Indonesia

Head of Electrical Division Staff of Electrical Division Jul 2019 – Oct 2020 Aug 2018 – Jul 2019

- Managed 5 people of Electrical Division to complete the electrical related task to build 3 robust humanoid robots that can play well and win at KRI (Kontes Robot Indonesia) in one year less
- Coordinated with Mechanical and Programming Division about tasks that needs to be done in period of time for better robot performance
- Found and debugged the 75% of electrical problems that occur on making humanoid robots
- Developed an interface button design from hardware design until behavior logic for state control of robots

EDUCATION

SMA NEGERI 5 SURABAYA

May 2016

INSTITUT TEKNOLOGI BANDUNG – BANDUNG, INDONESIA

Oct 2021

Bachelor of Engineering, Electrical Engineering

ADDITIONAL

Technical:

Robotic Development: MATLAB, Python, C++, ROS, Autodesk Inventor, Altium, Linux

Drone Development: Pixhawk, ArduPilot, PX4 Internet of Things: Arduino, MQTT, ESP32

Others: Microsoft Excel, Git Languages: Indonesia, English